cccapply.org 2004-02-11

# CCCApply - Privacy Policy Statement

**A Privacy Policy Statement from CCCApply**   

The Chancellor's Office California Community Colleges is offering students and prospective students CCCApply, an electronic service to complete and file admissions applications to individual California Community Colleges and supplements to those applications. Xap Corporation is the company that operates CCCApply on behalf of the Chancellor's Office California Community Colleges. The Chancellor's Office California Community Colleges and Xap Corporation recognize and respect the privacy interests of CCCApply users and are committed to protecting that privacy and keeping users informed about the privacy policy of CCCApply. Since the privacy policy that will be posted here may be modified from time to time to reflect changes in the manner in which CCCApply deals with personal information, we recommend that you regularly review the privacy policy statement, which will always reflect the then current policy. 

**WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT COVERS:**

  * The information we collect
  * CCCApply privacy policy and its exceptions
  * Consent
  * Minimum age of 13 required to establish an account
  * Ways in which personal identifying information may be used
  * With whom personal identifying information may be shared
  * Security measures to prevent misuse of information entrusted to CCCApply
  * Notification policy for California residents
  * Cookies
  * Links
  * Modifying and deleting your information
  * Questions

**THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**  
CCCApply collects personal information from you including your name, date of birth, address, e-mail address, telephone number, grade level, Social Security number and such additional information as you provide to complete admission applications to the California Community Colleges and Supplements to those applications. When the effective functioning of a CCCApply module does not require personal information, none is collected, and any such module can be accessed without providing any personal data. 

**CCCAPPLY PRIVACY POLICY AND ITS EXCEPTIONS**  
Except as set forth below, the personal identifying data you submit to CCCApply is not made available or distributed to third parties, unless authorized by law or with your express consent. In particular, the Chancellor's Office California Community Colleges and Xap Corporation will not sell or provide access to your personal information to any company, individual or organization for its use in marketing or commercial solicitation. 

**Exception regarding Directory Information**  
"Directory information" is that information regarding a student that is generally considered by the California Community Colleges not to be harmful to or an invasion of privacy of that student if disclosed. Directory information may be released by California Community Colleges without student consent. Directory information includes, but is not limited to, a student's name, address, telephone listing, date and place of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, and the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student. Some or all of the directory information relating to a particular student may be acquired by a community college through CCCApply. The community college you attend may designate additional information as directory information or choose not to release directory information at all. Check your college's catalog regarding its policy on directory information. If you do not want such information released, contact the admissions office at the college you are or will be attending.

**Other Exceptions to the Privacy Policy**  
When required by law to comply with any valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, regulation or court order, the Chancellor's Office and Xap Corporation will supply such information contained in your CCCApply account as that organization reasonably determines, based on the advice of counsel, it is legally required to supply. In addition, the Chancellor's Office and Xap Corporation may release specific information relevant to special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others, an attempted breach of security on the CCCApply site, or other operational requirements of the CCCApply site. 

When you log on to CCCApply, your browser will automatically transmit to CCCApply's server the IP address of your computer and type of browser you are using. Although your browser transmits the IP address of your computer, CCCApply does not associate this IP address with any personally identifiable information regarding you. CCCApply does not collect any personally identifiable information other than what users submit and their browsers transmit. 

There are situations where the Chancellor's Office or a community college you attend is not required to release personal information about you but is authorized by law to release such information without your consent. For example, personal information may be released to schools to which you are going to transfer, or to community college employees with legitimate educational interests in the information. Where such disclosures are authorized, generally the party receiving the information is not authorized to redisclose your personal information to others. 

**CONSENT**  
As discussed elsewhere in this policy, there are situations where the Chancellor's Office or a community college you attend may be required or authorized by law to release personally identifiable information about you. However, there are other situations in which such releases are prohibited unless you consent. The CCCApply electronic application form specifically asks you to consent to the release of personal information about you for certain identified purposes. You may decline to give your consent, but this will not prevent the Chancellor's Office or the community colleges you attend from using personally identifiable data about you in ways required or authorized by law. For example, answering "no" to the consent question will not prevent the release of directory information. Please see the prior discussion of directory information.   

**MINIMUM AGE OF 13 REQUIRED TO ESTABLISH AN ACCOUNT**  
CCCApply will not collect any information from persons who are not yet 13 years old. If you are under 13 years of age, you will not be permitted to open an account on CCCApply, to supply any personal identifying information to or through CCCApply, or to apply to California Community Colleges through CCCApply. 

If you are 13 years of age or older, you are encouraged to utilize all of CCCApply, which will help you to plan for your future education at California Community Colleges and to apply for admission to certain California Community Colleges through CCCApply. 

**WAYS IN WHICH PERSONAL IDENTIFYING INFORMATION MAY BE USED**  
CCCApply will use your personal identifying information to automatically fill out applications for admissions to California Community Colleges and supplements to those applications upon your instructions to do so. Your personal identifying information may also be used for the following purposes: 

  * We may use your identifying information to help administer the CCCApply website. 
  * Summary data representing a compilation of aggregate data representing CCCApply users may be collected by Xap Corporation and provided to the Chancellor's Office of the California Community Colleges, which may provide such data to various California Community Colleges and possibly others. No personal identifying information will be made available as part of these summary reports. Some examples of summary data are the number of monthly visitors to the site, the number of admission applications submitted over CCCApply, and the CCCApply functions utilized by students in specified age ranges. 

Information that is transmitted through CCCApply to the admissions office at one or more California Community Colleges may be used by the Chancellor's Office of the California Community Colleges or by a California Community College at which you enroll, which are outside the domain of CCCApply. Please review the sections entitled "Consent" and "Exception regarding Directory Information" in this privacy policy statement for information regarding the possible use of your personal identifying information after it is delivered by CCCApply. 

**WITH WHOM PERSONAL IDENTIFYING INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED**  
In each of the circumstances described below, data specifically required to perform a task you request will be made available to a recipient you designate: 

  * If you submit an application for admission to a California Community College through CCCApply, the personal data required to complete that application and any associated supplement will be provided on your behalf to the college to which you are applying. 
  * The personal data contained in the application and supplement may also be provided to the Chancellor's Office of the California Community Colleges. 

**SECURITY MEASURES TO PREVENT MISUSE OF INFORMATION ENTRUSTED TO CCCAPPLY**  
CCCApply enables the data you input to be encrypted when in route between your browser and the CCCApply™ server and when in route between the CCCApply server and some other browser or server. This practice helps prevent unauthorized third parties from intercepting and gaining access to your private data during transmission over the Internet. CCCApply uses 56-bit, Secure Socket Layer encryption supported by both Netscape's and Microsoft's current browsers. 

Data residing on the CCCApply server is password protected, and access is provided only to those employees of Xap Corporation who require such access to administer and maintain the CCCApply system or to provide requested customer support to users of CCCApply. Each Xap Corporation employee who has access to the data residing on the CCCApply server has agreed in writing to respect the privacy of all such personal data. 

**NOTIFICATION POLICY FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**  
In the event Xap reasonably believes that your unencrypted personal information has been accessed by an unauthorized person, Xap will notify you promptly regarding such unauthorized access, unless notification is delayed at the request of law enforcement agencies to avoid impeding a criminal investigation. Such notification will be made by e-mail, unless Xap does not have a valid e-mail address for you, in which case notification will be sent by United States mail to the home address indicated in your user account. For this purpose, personal information means (i) your first name or first initial, (ii) your surname and (iii) at least one of (a) your social security number, (b) your driver's license or alternative identification card number, or (c) a financial account number, credit card account number or debit card account number associated with you, in combination with any required security or access code or password needed to access such account.   

**COOKIES**  
A cookie is a small file that a website transfers to a user's computer, which may then be stored on its hard drive. CCCApply uses cookies to remember you and personalize your web-viewing experience by keeping track of your session when logged on to CCCApply. Cookies enable you to maintain continuity as you move from page to page on CCCApply and to avoid the nuisance of being asked to provide the same information repeatedly. Cookies also allow us to make sure that only your browser can exchange information regarding your account with our servers. Cookies cannot be used to steal personal information or to gain access to information that you did not directly provide. The cookies we use are set when you log on to CCCApply and are erased when you log off CCCApply or completely close your browser. 

**Don't want cookies?**  
Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you don't want cookies, you can set your browser to disable or refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being used. You should note, however, that various CCCApply services might not function properly when cookies are not utilized. 

**LINKS**  
CCCApply™ contains links to other sites having privacy policies that may differ from those of CCCApply™. The Chancellor's Office California Community Colleges and Xap Corporation are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any websites to which CCCApply™ links.   

**MODIFYING AND DELETING YOUR INFORMATION**  
You may update, otherwise modify or delete from the data stored on CCCApply™ any personal information you previously provided. To modify personal information, (1) log on to CCCApply™, (2) access either your user profile or an application containing the information you want to change, and (3) modify that information using standard word-processing techniques. To delete personal information, (1) log on to CCCApply™, (2) access your user profile, and (3) delete the information you want to remove from CCCApply™ using standard word-processing techniques. Please recognize that if you delete information, it will no longer be available on CCCApply™ so that, for example, if a college to which you previously submitted an application were to attempt to retrieve that application from CCCApply™ after you made the deletion the deleted information would no longer be accessible. Similarly, when accessed over CCCApply™ information that has been updated or otherwise modified will appear in its then most current form, rather than in the form in which it may have been submitted at some earlier time.   

**QUESTIONS**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement and the privacy practices on this site, you may contact a representative of Xap Corporation by e-mail or telephone as follows:

Xap Corporation  
(800) GO-TO-XAP or (310) 842-9800
